RG 004:025, Cheshire Probate Court
Connecticut State Library
Cheshire Probate Court records
1829-2007
bulk 1829-1972
Connecticut State Library
Connecticut. Probate Court (Cheshire District)
47.5 cubic feet
Probate record books, 1829-2007, bulk 1829-1972 (includes certificates of elections and oaths of office of judge of probate, 1910-2007); Probate files, 1829-1912.
RG004_025
1915-023, 2011-097, and 2012-021
Historical Note
Cheshire, New Haven County, Town established in May 1780, Parent Town: Wallingford
The Cheshire Probate District was constituted May 27, 1829, from the Wallingford Probate District. The Cheshire Probate District merged with the Southington Probate District to create the Cheshire - Southington Probate District which serves the municipalities of Cheshire and Southington.
Town of Cheshire, Probate District chronology:
May 1780 - May 26, 1829, Wallingford District
May 27, 1829 - January 4, 2011, Cheshire District
January 5, 2011 - Present, Cheshire - Southington District
For Probate Court contact information and hours of operation see,.
Scope and Content
Probate record books, Volumes 1-63, 1829-2007, bulk 1829-1972. See Alternative Form Available note below.
Probate files, 1829-1912. Probate files may consist of estates, conservatorships, guardianships, commitments, and insolvencies.
Inventory control book, 1829-1912 (coverage). Also known as the Godard Digest, it is a list of probate files transferred to the Connecticut State Library. It was compiled at the Connecticut State Library under the direction of State Librarian George S. Godard.
Arrangement
Record books are numbered consecutively from 1 to 63.
Probate files are arranged alphabetically in one series.
Other Finding Aid
Record Books: Index cards for the record books have been scanned. Ask History and Genealogy staff for assistance. Note: CSL does not hold any original record books. See Alternate Form Available section for volumes available on microfilm.
Probate Files: The Probate Estate Papers Index, located in the index corridor adjacent to the History and Genealogy Reading Room, has two parts, a general index covering most of the state, and a Hartford Probate District index covering Hartford and some surrounding towns, 1820-1920. The index cards are arranged alphabetically by individual's last name and first names. The cards have the individual's name, town of residence, probate district, and list of items contained in the estate packet. To request retrieval of an estate packet, copy at least the estate name, file date, and probate district name from the index card. The probate files in Accession 1915-023 are represented in this index.
Index Terms
Subjects:
Probate records -- Connecticut -- Cheshire
Places:
Cheshire (Conn.)
Restrictions on Access
Researchers should first consult use copies when available. See Alternate Form Available Section below.
Accessions 2011-097 and 2012-021, Record books, 1829-2007, bulk 1829-1972, are stored at an off-site facility and therefore may not be available on a same-day basis.
See the policy.
Alternative Form Available
Record books, Volumes 1-6, 8, 10, 13-14, 16-17, 22, 1829-1920; probate files 1829-1912 (Accession 1915-023); and inventory control book (Godard Digest) were microfilmed by the Genealogical Society of Utah and are available for use in the History and Genealogy reading room or through the.
Provenance
The probate files in accession 1915-023 were transferred to the Connecticut State Library on the following dates (with date span of files): September 28, 1915 (1829-1912).
The record books in accession 2011-097 were transferred to the Connecticut State Library on January 11, 2011.
The record books in accession 2012-021 were transferred to the Connecticut State Library on March 6, 2012.
Container List
- Record books, 1829-2007, bulk 1829-1937; 12 cubic feet (23 volumes); 2011-097
  - Records, 1829-1851 (Volume 1)
  - Records, 1841-1849 (Volume 2)
  - Records, 1849-1858 (Volume 3)
  - Orders and decrees, 1854-1866 (Volume 4)
    On spine: "Records"
  - Records, 1858-1865 (Volume 5)
  - Records, 1864-1874 (Volume 6)
  - Orders and decrees, 1867-1877 (Volume 7)
  - Records, 1873-1881 (Volume 8)
  - Orders and decrees, 1877-1887 (Volume 9)
  - Records, 1881-1890 (Volume 10)
    On spine: "Manuscript"
  - Bonds, 1881-1910 (Volume 11)
  - Orders and decrees, 1887-1898 (Volume 12)
  - Records, 1887-1894 (Volume 13)
  - Records, 1893-1901 (Volume 14)
  - Orders and decrees, 1898-1908 (Volume 15)
  - Records, 1900-1907 (Volume 16)
    Also contains certificates of election, 1910-1913
  - Records, 1908-1913 (Volume 17)
  - Orders and decrees, 1907-1915 (Volume 16)
  - Bonds, 1911-1937 (Volume 19)
  - Records, 1913-1915 (Volume 20)
    Also contains certificates of election and oaths of office of judge of probate, 1914-2007
  - Orders and decrees, 1915-1923 (Volume 21)
  - Records, 1915-1920 (Volume 22)
  - Records, 1920-1925 (Volume 23)
- Record books, 1923-1972; 26 cubic feet (40 volumes); 2012-021
  Volumes titled "Records" below have "Manuscript" on the spine.
  - Records, 1925-1928 (Volume 24)
  - Orders and decrees, 1923-1936 (Volume 25)
  - Records, 1926-1932 (Volume 26)
  - Records, 1930-1935 (Volume 27)
  - Records, 1935-1938 (Volume 28)
  - Records, 1936-1947 (Volume 29)
  - Records, 1935-1938 (Volume 28)
  - Orders and decrees, 1936-1947 (Volume 29)
  - Bonds, 1937-1958 (Volume 30)
  - Records, 1938-1941 (Volume 31)
  - Records, 1941-1944 (Volume 32)
  - Records, 1941-1945 (Volume 33)
  - Records, 1945-1948 (Volume 34)
  - Records, 1948-1950 (Volume 35)
  - Orders and decrees, 1947-1954 (Volume 36)
  - Records, 1950-1952 (Volume 37)
  - Records, 1952-1955 (Volume 38)
  - Records, 1953-1955 (Volume 39)
  - Orders and decrees, 1955 (Volume 40)
  - Records, 1956-1960 (Volume 41)
  - Records, 1955-1958 (Volume 42)
  - Bonds, 1958-1972 (Volume 43)
  - Records, 1957-1959 (Volume 44)
  - Records, 1958-1960 (Volume 45)
  - Records, 1960-1962 (Volume 46)
  - Records, 1961-1963 (Volume 47)
  - Records, 1962-1963 (Volume 48)
  - Records, 1962-1964 (Volume 49)
  - Records, 1964-1965 (Volume 50)
  - Records, 1964-1967 (Volume 51)
  - Records, 1965-1967 (Volume 52)
  - Records, 1965-1967 (Volume 53)
  - Records, 1966-1968 (Volume 54)
  - Records, 1966-1968 (Volume 55)
  - Records, 1962-1969 (Volume 56)
  - Records, 1965-1969 (Volume 57)
  - Records, 1967-1970 (Volume 58)
  - Records, 1967-1970 (Volume 59)
  - Records, 1968-1971 (Volume 60)
  - Records, 1970-1971 (Volume 61)
  - Records, 1969-1972 (Volume 62)
  - Records, 1966-1972 (Volume 63)
- Probate files, 1829-1912; 9.5 cubic feet; 1915-023
  - Allen - Andrews (Drawer 1)
  - Anthony -Beach, B. (Drawer 2)
  - Beach, C. - Benham, L. (Drawer 3)
  - Benham, M. - Bradley, R. (Drawer 4)
  - Bradley, S. - Bristol, P. (Drawer 5)
  - Bristol, O. - Brown (Drawer 6)
  - Bryan - Clark (Drawer 7)
  - Coe - Cornwall (Drawer 8)
  - Cota - Doolittle, E. (Drawer 9)
  - Doolittle, F. - Few (Drawer 10)
  - Fields - Gaylord (Drawer 11)
  - Gellis - Hall (Drawer 12)
  - Hammick - Hitchcock, I. (Drawer 13)
  - Hitchcock, J. - Hotchkiss, D. (Drawer 14)
  - Hotchkiss, E. - Humiston, B. (Drawer 15)
  - Humiston, C. - Ives, H. (Drawer 16)
  - Ives, I. - Kimball (Drawer 17)
  - King - Lombra (Drawer 18)
  - Lord - Monson, L. (Drawer 19)
  - Monson, M. - Morse (Drawer 20)
  - Moss - Munson (Drawer 21)
  - Murphy - Pardee, G. (Drawer 22)
  - Pardee, H. - Platt, L. (Drawer 23)
  - Platt, M. - Rogers, J. (Drawer 24)
  - Rogers, K. - Smith, R. (Drawer 25)
  - Smith, S. - Terrill, B. (Drawer 26)
  - Terrell, C. - Tuttle, L. (Drawer 27)
  - Tuttle, M. - Wickham (Drawer 28)
  - Wildman - Z; Miscellaneous (Drawer 29)
- Inventory control book, 1829-1912; T003073
  Index of probate files in accession 1915-023
  Also known as the Godard Digest